Finding aid for the Campus Cat records CA.MS.00097
Smith College Archives
Campus Cat records
1918-1952
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.00097
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
Campus Cat was a publication created by Smith students in 1918. Its contents provided information to the campus about going-ons, events, activities, and poked fun at the rituals, trials, and stresses of academia and life on the Smith campus. Material includes most issues of the Campus Cat, press releases and other Campus Cat related publications.
Biographical / Historical
"Published when the spirit moves", Campus Cat was a publication created by Smith students in 1918. Its contents provided information to the campus about going-ons, events, activities, and poked fun at the rituals, trials, and stresses of academia and life on the Smith campus. It was a popular publication, provoking many other related publications such as Freshman Eti-Cat and the Campus Cat-alogue, among others.
The Campus Cat was written by a group of students whose sarcasm and wit are clearly evident in each issue of the publication. It was a highly coveted publication and to be included in the group of Campus Cat writers was to hold a position of prestige. The publication ceased in 1929.
However, in 1949, students brought the Cat back. The Campus Cat was now funded by the college. Each issue, of which there were four a year, was bound in program form. Again, to write for it was to hold a position of prestige. The issues published between 1948 and 1952 were written by the same group of students upon whose graduation, the Cat had lived its second out of nine lives.
Scope and Contents
Within the archival box containing the Campus Cat, issues of the Campus Cat are incomplete. Press releases and other Campus Cat related publications are included in the files. The folders are arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
The Smith College Archives has bound copies of the Campus Cat for the years 1918-22, 1922-23, January-June 1924, 1948-49, and 1949-50. These are located under Student Publications.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Issues of the Campus Cat and related publications were collected by the Smith College Archives as they were published.
Smith College--Students--Social life and customs.
- Campus Cat, 1918-1920s (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat, 1924 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat, 1925 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat, 1926-27 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat, 1927 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat, 1928-29 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat, 1948-49 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat, 1949-50 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat, 1950-51 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat, 1951-52 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat-alogue, 1922-23 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat Alumnae, 1924 (Box 3112)
- Campus Catechism, 1923 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat Monthly, 1928 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat Publications, 1929-30 (Box 3112)
- Campus Cat Yearbook, 1930s (Box 3112)
- Can-It-By Fair, 1929 (Box 3112)
- Cat's Ghost, 1926 (Box 3112)
- Freshman Eti-Cat, 1923 (Box 3112)
- General, 1918; 1948; 1952 (Box 3112)
- Kampus Kitten Klarion, 1923 (Box 3112)
- Photographs, 1921-22; 1951 (Box 3112)
- Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1923 (Box 3112)